A Guide to the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts - Lands Redeemed by the Executive, 1792-1859
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts - Lands Redeemed by the Executive, 1792-1859
The Library of Virginia
APA 554
.9 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts (1776-1928)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Auditor of Public Accounts in 1913.
Biographical Information
The General Assembly passed an act on 20 December 1791 authorizing the governor to transmit to sheriffs lists of land on which taxes were delinquent, so that the sheriffs might sell the land. An act passed on 9 February 1814 required the reversion of the land to the Literary Fund if no bid was received, to be held for future sale.
On 20 February 1817 the General Assembly passed an act authorizing the governor to redeem, or purchase for the state, certain lands already sold for taxes. The governor appointed agents to make the payments on his behalf, using public money. The purpose of the act was to discourage the practice of purchasing land for taxes, then holding it for speculation rather then settling and cultivating it. Subsequent acts were passed for the same purpose.
Scope and Content
Records, 1792-1859, including Correspondence, 1817 (1 item); Agent's bonds for agents to redeem land, 1817 (4 items); Auditor's receipts, 1851-1859 (42 items); County lists of lands sold by the sheriff for nonpayment of taxes and redeemed by agent for the Governor, 1816-1817 (4 folders); Deed (Albemarle Co. - Mathew Rodes to David Rodes), 1822 (1 item); Treasurer's receipts, 1792-1831 (29 folders); and Warrant, 1817 (1 item).
County lists consist of lists of lands sold by the sheriff for delinquent taxes and include the name of the delinquent land owner, number of acres, amount of tax and damages, name and residence of the purchaser, purchase amount, fee for clerks and aggregate totals. Each bond contains the signatures of the claimant and securities, the date, and the amount of the bond.
These records are part of Auditor of Public Accounts. Administration of State Government: Revenue Assessment and Collection - Land Taxes. Redemption of Land.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- Agent's bonds, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Auditor's receipts, 1851-1859. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- County lists - Amherst, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- County lists - Bototourt, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- County lists - Hanover, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- County lists - James City, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- County lists - Louisa, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- County lists - Mathews, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- County lists - Northumberland, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- County lists - Orange, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- County lists - Pittsylvania, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- County lists - Prince Edward, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- County lists - Prince William, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- County lists - Rockbridge, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- County lists - Shenandoah, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- County lists - Tazewell, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- County lists - Wythe, 1816. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- County lists - Amherst, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- County lists - Bath, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- County lists - Bedford, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- County lists - Botetourt, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- County lists - Buckingham, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- County lists - Campbell, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- County lists - Grayson, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- County lists - Hanover, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- County lists - Henrico, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- County lists - James City, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- County lists - Lee, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- County lists - Louisa, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- County lists - Mathews, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- County lists - Northumberland, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- County lists - Orange, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- County lists - Pittsylvania, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- County lists - Prince Edward, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- County lists - Prince William, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- County lists - Rockbridge, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- County lists - Shenandoah, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- County lists - Tazewell, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- County lists - Wythe, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Deed for land sold by the sheriff of Albemarle County (Mathew Rodes to David Rodes), 1822. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Rough letter transmitting funds to be redeemed, 1817 Apr 9. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Treasurer's receipts - Bedford Co., 1822. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Treasurer's receipts - Campbell Co., 1792-1830. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Treasurer's receipts - Caroline Co., 1828-1830. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Treasurer's receipts - Charles City Co., 1802-1813. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Treasurer's receipts - Charlotte Co., 1796-1830. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Treasurer's receipts - Chesterfield Co., 1797-1830. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Treasurer's receipts - Culpeper Co., 1796-1828. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Treasurer's receipts - Cumberland Co., 1797-1809. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Treasurer's receipts - Dinwiddie, 1793-1830. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Treasurer's receipts - Elizabeth City Co., 1820. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Treasurer's receipts - Fairfax Co., 1821-1830. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Treasurer's receipts - Fauquier Co., 1805-1814. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Treasurer's receipts - Fluvanna Co., 1793-1830. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Treasurer's receipts - Franklin Co., 1793-1828. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Treasurer's receipts - Frederick Co., 1807-1830. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Treasurer's receipts - Grayson Co., 1818-1826. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Treasurer's receipts - Greenbrier Co., 1831. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Treasurer's receipts - Pendleton Co., 1819. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Treasurer's receipts - Randolph Co., 1826. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Treasurer's receipts - Rockbridge Co., 1818-1829. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Treasurer's receipts - Shenandoah Co., 1818. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Treasurer's receipts - Tazewell Co., 1828. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Treasurer's receipts - Wythe Co., 1828. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Treasurer's receipts - Manchester, Town of, 1794. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Treasurer's receipts - Mixed counties, 1792-1820. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Treasurer's receipts - Mixed counties, 1811 Nov-1812 Jan. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Treasurer's receipts - Mixed counties, 1812 Feb-Mar. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Treasurer's receipts - Mixed counties, 1812 Mar-Nov. (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Treasurer's receipts - Mixed counties, 1816-1817. (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Warrant, 1817. (Box 2, Folder 22)